Hey folks, thanks for having me. Um, I'm
going to talk a bit today about
automating uh large scale refactors and
like other large highly automatable
tasks uh with AI agents. These are tasks
that can't really be like oneshotted
with an agent today uh but are highly
automatable. They involve a lot of wrote
work uh that engineers don't typically
like to do.
Uh a bit about me. Uh my name is Robert
Brennan. I'm the CEO and co-founder at
OpenHance. Uh we're an MIT licensed uh
AI coding agent. Uh started in early
2024. Uh I would say we're the leading
open source coding agent if you're
looking for an open source alternative
to something like cloud code or dev.
Uh my background in particular is in a
mixture of natural language processing
and dev tools. Uh so I've been working
in commercial open source for a while.
Uh and I'm just generally very excited
about what uh what LLM are doing for
developer productivity today.
uh a quick like history of AI coding for
those who uh have not been um uh on top
of this for the last few years. Uh we
started really with like context unaware
code snippets. So uh being able to
generate code uh you know basically
asking chatbt without any kind of
context about your codebase you know
please write an algorithm that'll do X.
Um about a year later we started getting
things like GitHub copilot which could
take some context in your codebase that
could see kind of what the surrounding
code was like uh and generate the next
few lines of code or generate some code
based on you know the context of your
particular codebase.
Uh then the next year uh 2024 when Devon
and openance were born uh we got this
this next leap forward where agents were
not uh agents basically uh came onto the
scene and were able to not just generate
code but they could run the code that
they generated. uh they could uh you
know Google an error message that comes
out of the code basically do the entire
inner loop of development in an
automated fashion. This is a huge leap
forward. Uh and what we're seeing now is
is the next leap where you've got uh
agents that are working together um or
you know taking a task and spreading it
out across multiple agents so you can
get a lot more done faster.
Uh some examples of of those like large
scale projects that are more appropriate
for you know many different agents
working rather than a single agent are
things like um you know upgrading a
programming language through a major
version bump like Python 2 to Python 3,
rewriting a codebase from one from one
language to another. Uh large scale
refactors um you know really really
anything that uh is going to involve a
lot of wte work uh but is too large of a
task to fit in like a single PR. uh it's
too much. You know, it's something you
could imagine giving to a team of
engineers rather than a single engineer
or something you could imagine uh
accomplishing over the series of several
different poll requests where you've
gone several check-ins to see, you know,
are things going well? Are things going
in the right direction? Do we need to
reorient?
Um there's a bunch of reasons why uh
these kinds of tasks just can't be like
thrown at a single agent today. Um uh
some of these are problems with the
agents themselves, right? There are some
limitations that the LLM have. Um there
are also just like some human problems
involved here. Uh you know, a lot of
times humans uh struggle to actually
decompose tasks for agents. Um they
can't convey their own intuition. Uh and
there's still this need for the human to
kind of review each each output step.
That's that's a big bottleneck in the
process.
Uh a handful of things are changing here
making this more of a a reality. Uh one
is just the underlying LLM technology is
getting better. We're seeing longer
context windows. Uh inference costs are
going down. We're seeing LM getting
better at planning and task
decomposition. Uh but I think more
importantly,
we're seeing uh some some evolution in
the ecosystem itself. Uh we're seeing
agents that aren't just like single
threaded running on your computer, but
are more cloud-based. Um agents that are
running all in their own sandbox, so
they're not stepping on each other's
toes. Um we're also seeing interfaces
for for wrangling multiple agents at
once and coordinating them together. Uh,
and we're getting better intuition for
as humans for how these agents behave.
You know, what can they accomplish? What
can't they accomplish? How do I need to
hold their hand to make sure they're
able to get this done?
Uh, I'll talk a little bit about, you
know, the different workflows that we
see when people are working with
multiple agents. But just to start, um,
this is a typical, you know,
agent-driven development task, uh, for
humans today. If you're if you're
working on a single single task, so
you're going to, you know, submit a
single PR. Uh, typically you you throw a
prompt at the agent. The agent works for
5 10 15 minutes on its own, hopefully
unsupervised, or maybe you're hitting
the the Y key with quad code. Uh, and
then it gets to the end of its task and
you review the output. Maybe, you know,
you're looking at a PR on GitHub or
you're looking at your diff and VS code.
Uh, and then you might accept that and
merge it or you might do another turn of
the loop, prompt the agent again, say,
"Hey, you you messed up on this part.
You know, try and redo it." Pretty
simple. simple development loop here.
Things get a little bit more complicated
when you've got multiple agents all
working in parallel. Um, typically this
workflow involves decomposing the tasks
to be accomplished. You know, say you're
you're migrating from Python 2 to Python
3. You might say, "Okay, I'm going to
start with this directory and then move
on to this directory." Um, you know,
you're going to break up this problem
into into individual tasks that can be
assigned out and and worked on in
parallel. Uh, then you're going to have
all these agents uh working on them. And
then at the end, you're going to try and
get all those results together in like a
single PR or merge into the main branch
al together so that you've got the
entire task done.
But there's still a pretty big
bottleneck here. You you're going to
need to review the code at each point in
the in the process, right? Uh for each
of those individual agents, you're going
to need to look at its output and make
sure that it did the right thing,
potentially prompt it again uh and
refine your strategy over time. uh you
can start to automate this with like
CI/CD um and having agents do do their
own code review. But at the end of the
day, like this is an important step in
the process is that you've got a human
being reviewing each agent's output.
Uh a quick kind of overview of what this
actually looks like in practice uh using
git. Um typically what I will do is I'll
start a new branch uh that's that's
going to be like my meta branch for all
the work that's being done here. Um,
I'll usually add some kind of high level
context there. Uh, usually checked into
the branch either in agents.mmd or with
open hands. We have this concept of
microaggents that can be checked in. Um,
and then that's kind of in place for all
the agents that I'm going to kick off on
this branch. Uh, I'll often put some
scaffolding in place. This is a really
simple example of using like a V1 and V0
directory, but um, sometimes I might if
I'm like migrating state systems in
React, I might put in some scaffold that
allows me to live in both worlds at
once. Uh, and then you kind of set off
these agents, right? You break down the
task into uh multiple different parts.
You send off each agent maybe on a
different directory or a different
component, a different part of the
problem that they can work on
independently. Uh and then at the end
you can rip out the scaffolding, get
everything merged together and get it
merged into domain.
Uh task decomposition is a big important
part of this. Um figuring out how to uh
break down your goal into things that
each each agent can actually accomplish
uh can be really difficult and sometimes
takes some iteration. Uh but you're
generally looking for something that an
agent will be able to oneshot or get
close to oneshotting. Um things that can
be done in a single commit or at least a
single pull request. Uh and in
particular, you want things that you can
verify very quickly and easily. Um you
want to be pretty confident that if
CI/CD is passing, the agent's done the
thing. uh or that you can like click
around in the UI and verify that it's
actually done.
Um I'm not going to go uh for the sake
of time into into these too much, but um
uh you might go like piece by piece
here. You might just say file by file or
directory by directory.
Uh you might uh pull out a whole
dependency tree and try to work on the
things that have the fewest dependencies
first. U so you might do like your
utility files first and then you know
some middle middle parts and then like
finally come down to your your main.py
Pi
uh and you might do this like scaffold
uh and iterate process that I mentioned
earlier like um you know I I had one
task where I was migrating state
management systems in React. I set up a
scaffold that would allow me to use both
state management systems in parallel uh
so that the test would continue to pass
as I migrated component by component.
Once I got all the components migrated
uh then I ripped out the scaffolding and
just was living in the new world with
the new state management system.
Uh another big problem here is concrete.
So these agents are going to learn as um
you know one one naive approach here
would be to just share everything. Maybe
you've got one agent that's that's doing
everything itself iteratively um or each
agent can see every other agents
history. Uh but this is you know very uh
kind of heavy weight. It's it's too much
information to throw out all these
agents. Um you're a going to get very
confused very quickly about what's going
on.
Uh a more um uh typical approach I would
say is that a human being is passing
context to these agents. So if you see
agent A struggling with uh you know a
particular library that's being updated
uh you might say okay I figured that
out. I'm now going to tell all the other
agents don't use that library. Um you
could also manually modify one of these
files that's being checked in your
agents.md or an openance micro agent to
encode that knowledge. Um downsides here
are that it involves you like manually
intervening. uh you have to like watch
these agents and like identify oh that's
a that's a lesson that was learned and
now I can propagate that to the other
agents.
So the uh uh another another more
automated way would be to have a shared
file like this agents.mmd uh tell the
agents to like put new information into
that file, check it in. Uh downsides are
like the automation causes agents to
sometimes learn on important things. So
there's there's a bit of a trade-off
here. Uh when you're the gate, uh you
can make sure that they're only learning
important things.
Um, and then a more uh kind of
future-looking uh piece here would be to
allow the agents to actually pass
messages to each other. U so you can
actually give them each a tool that
allows them to send messages into the
other agents and say, "Hey, you know, I
learned, you know, library version 1.2.3
doesn't work well. Upgrade to 1.2.4."
Um, they can broadcast to all the other
agents. Um, and you can see a quick
example here using the open hands SDK.
Uh, that's all I've got for now, but
would love any questions that you'all
have.
[Applause]
Thank you so much. You mentioned context
window increasing and I found that this
was not a very strong trend. I mean if
you take Eric Schmid predicting and
limited context windows by the end of
24. Uh do you am I wrong? Is it actually
happening or or is that something that
will take a lot more time? Yeah, it it
see
that is probably the the like least
helpful as agents evolve here. Um it
does seem uh like even when you do get
the bigger context windows, uh the
agents the more context you throw at
them, the more confused they get, right?
So even then makes sense to cut out
unnecessary context as much as possible.
So when you're doing very large scale
tasks like this, a lot of times the the
best strategy is to make sure that um uh
each agent is only seeing the context
that is important for this particular
part of the task, right? Um even if you
have an infinite context window, if
you're throwing, you know, everything
that's been done in this this refactor
at an agent, it's going to like have to
pick through needles, find find the
needle hack to find the information
actually needs to push on it particular
part of the task. So that's a very small
piece of of uh you know things getting
better here.
>> Thank you for the great talk. Um very
inspiring. um on your last slide for the
message passing I've never never
incurred to me um of of like telling my
agents that they took uh talk to have
messages sending uh to each other. Um,
is there like the way that I would
imagining them and I'm sorry I'm using
claw code but uh um then then I'm I'm
writing messages so I'm kind of like in
the middle of kind of like interrupting
sending them almost is is that the same
thing? And to that question is is the
the receiving end kind of like opening
up like a special channel kind of like
okay when there's output information I
stop and maybe rewind or something is
like something special logic in there or
are we basically just like throwing more
information in a running agent?
>> Yeah. So um in this particular example
we're basically just throwing more
information into the into the context
window in the same way that you might
just type something into the chat window
and say you know don't use version
one.2.3.
Um I have seen an implementation too
where the agent had a like receive
messages call and there was like a
messages stack in the middle. Uh to be
clear I have not seen this uh
productionized very well like just it's
still very experimental. Um but I think
I think both are potentially potentially
good options. One where the agent has to
pull information in and one where uh
it's getting that that new information
thrown at it. Uh but it is nice that it
doesn't have to um uh
you know a lot of times some something
will be learned in the process here that
the agent's not going to think oh
somebody else might have discovered this
problem already. It's just to kind of
push information at the agent
>> and make that explicit that that change
of information. Yeah
>> exactly.
>> Yeah. Thanks.
Thank you for the talk. Um those the
tasks you are addressing here are pretty
advanced. Uh and on the other hand I I
I've heard about your company because
you are one of the leaders of three pen
verified. Uh congrats for that. Um but I
don't think that benchmarks currently
are are good way to evaluate this kind
of task because they are just basically
too complex too much human in the loop
involvement. What is your way to assess
your the current performance of open
hands and what is for this kind of task
what is the the current relevant
benchmark or the most relevant
benchmark?
>> Yeah, this is something we're actively
working on. Um, you know, we actually
put one of our researchers on
specifically this problem. Uh, and he
has been reviewing the literature a
bunch. There's really no benchmarks for
these very large tasks because they're
not entirely automatable. You need a
human in the loop. If you're going to
say migrate a codebase from Python 2 to
Python 3 or working on Spark 2 to three
migrations that go all the Java
transformations, if you look at the
papers, they all focus on a single
codebase. And it's always a um uh a
review of like what it took to get
agents to automate most of this task
with a human thinking about it and using
their own intuition for the codebase
etc. So uh to some degree it's like it's
it's based on vibes like are we getting
better at these sorts of tasks over time
by using these different strategies. Um
I could see having a benchmark that is a
little bit more uh human oriented like
you give the task to a human and see how
much they can get done after uh doing
some training and then you know working
with agents. Uh but it's a very hard
thing to measure in that sort of pure
way that we measure tasks.
>> Um I'm trying to be really quick. Um
actually there's a benchmark that was
released yesterday by SCI that probably
address what you mentioned.
It looks very interesting. Um, two quick
question. The first one is do you use
open hands to develop open hands?
>> Yeah, I think uh close to half the
commits open hands now are done by open
hands. Um, and second question
specifically for display is it something
that is completely custom to open hands
or are you trying to implement agent
rings? Oh, we we are looking at each
agent specifically. Uh the SDK is
something that we're actively working
on. Uh and we're thinking about um uh
how do we implement either something
like this is totally custom or an A2A
more framework.
>> Thank you.
>> I had one more question about the
context sharing. So you were talking
about like you could give a file or the
human could determine what's best.
Couldn't a agent be developed
specifically for contact sharing and
then they understand what happens and
then they have the full context and
determine what is given to an agent.
That that could be a really neat one
where you just have each one looking at
one agent looking at what every other
agent's doing. If I go back to my uh
timeline slide,
I will put it as an open question. What
happens in 2026? But I think manager
agents are going to be more of a thing.
You got one in the back.
>> Yeah.
>> You mentioned uh at the end there about
how agents can share their knowledge.
How do you define the knowledge? How do
you define a learning? What how would it
get back and shared?
>> It's a good question. Uh you know when
you as a human see it, you know it,
right? You see, you know, I've seen
three different agents struggle with
this one part of the task. If I just add
this two sentences the prompt, they'll
figure it out much faster. U I would say
agents are iffy on recognizing uh when
something is like you know worthy of
being shared or not. Uh so sometimes it
is nice to have a human in that loop and
uh deciding what what learnings are
going to go in. Um you can have it set
up so that like the agents are like
making PRs back to the agents.mmd or to
a micro agent saying um you know here's
what I want to add to the context
window. Um, and then you can either
approve or deny. Um, they tend to be a
little bit too trigger happy with like,
oh, I learned a new thing. I put it in
here. I learned a new thing. Put it in
here.
>> Thank you. Thank you.
[Applause]